Divya Hemnani

Developer

Experienced and dedicated Data Analyst with several years of experience identifying efficiencies and problem areas within data streams, while communicating needs for projects. Adept at receiving and monitoring data from multiple data streams, including Accesses, SQL and Excel data sources. Bringing forth the ability to synthesize quantitative information and interact effectively with colleagues and clients with focus on enhancing digital skills like Data Science.

Employment History

- Tata Consultancy Services, Ahmedabad
- System Engineer

June 2022 to Present

- Leverage in advanced analytical techniques to extract actionable insights from complex datasets, driving informed decision-making and optimizing business processes
- Experienced in developing and maintaining reporting dashboards, I communicate findings effectively to stakeholders, facilitating data-driven strategies and initiatives. With a keen attention to detail and a passion for problem solving
- Tata Consultancy Services, Ahmedabad
- o Intern

Jan 2022 to April 2022

- I have gained experience with the Microsoft Azure Platform, delved into Serverless computing and also explored the Power Platform during the work
- CreArt Solutions, Ahmedabad
- o Intern

June 2021 to July 2021

I acquired fundamental knowledge of software development, including the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) and gained insights into how organizations operate on live projects. Additionally, I created small-scale projects using PHP.

Education

 B.E. – Information Technology (2018 – 2022)
 Silver Oak College of Engineering and Technology Ahmedabad
 CGPA 8.89

○ **H.S.C. – Science** (2017 – 2018)

Sai Shree Academy Ratlam Percentage 88%

o **S.S.C.** (2016 – 2017)

Sai Shree Academy Ratlam Percentage 87%

- ◆ Ahmedabad
- **C** 7600491335
- divya11hemnani@gmail.com
- GitHub
- in LinkedIn

Skills

Programming Skills

Python (Pandas, Scikit Learn) SOL

Data Visualization

Excel / Google Sheets Matplotlib

Tools

Microsoft Power BI
Microsoft SQL Server

Web Development

HTML CSS

JavaScript

Libraries

React JS

Certifications

Microsoft Certifications:

- PL-300 Power BI Data Analyst Associate
- AZ-900 Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
- PL-200 Microsoft Power Platform Functional Consultant

Udemy Certifications:

- Python for data science and data analytics
- Full stack web developer bootcamp

Projects

 I Analysed sales data from an e-commerce platform to identify trends and insights. Conducted exploratory data analysis (EDA) to visualize sales performance.

Techniques used: Data cleaning, data visualization (e.g. bar charts, line plots), Basic statistical analysis (mean, median, standard deviation), Excel and Google Sheets for data manipulation and visualization.

- I developed a Power BI dashboard to illustrate the migration progress across multiple workstreams, in accordance with project specifications.
 Techniques used: Data gathering by utilizing SQL server, Data visualization, integration, customization to ensure alignment with project goals.
- In a personal endeavour, I crafted an HR analytics dashboard utilizing the Power BI platform.

Techniques Used: Gathered HR data from various sources such in csv form. Cleaned and pre-processed the raw data to remove duplicates, missing values, and inconsistencies. Created relationships between different data tables to establish meaningful connections. Designed visually appealing and insightful visualization to present HR metrics effectively. Leveraged Power BI features such as DAX calculations, custom visuals, and Power Query for advanced analytics and data manipulation.

- I possess hands-on experience developing Power App forms for real-world projects, leveraging SharePoint as the backend data repository.
 Techniques Used: Power Apps development, SharePoint integration, and database management.
- Proficiently executed automation initiatives utilizing PowerShell scripts and SQL servers.

Techniques Used: PowerShell, C#, SQL servers.